Register of the Poland. Ministerstwo Informacji i Dokumentacji Records, 1939-1945
Hoover Institution Archives
- POLES DEPORTED TO THE SOVIET UNION, 1939-1945
  - General
    - Memoirs
      - "Pod Sowiecka Inwazja," n.d. (Box 114., Folder 1)
      - "Prisoner's Tale" by L. Biesiakowska, n.d. (Folder 2)
      - "Red Freedom" by 'Tourist,' n.d. (Folder 3)
      - "Relacje o obozie katorznym" by Professor A. Skapski, n.d. (Folder 4)
      - "Rzeczywistosc Sowiecka," n.d. (Folder 5)
      - "The Truth Has to Be Told," n.d. (Folder 6)
      - "W Kraju-wiezienia" by Stanislaw Lubodziecki, n.d. (Folder 7)
      - "Wspomnienia," n.d. (Box 115., Folder 1)
      - "Wspomnienia z Rosii" by Jan Zarno, n.d. (Folder 2)
      - "Wspomnienia z tamtego swiata," n.d. (Folder 3)
      - "Zalosny etap" by Maria Goldman, n.d. (Folder 4)
      - "Moje przezycia, sporstrzezenia I wrazenia na zestaniu w ZSSR" by Erika Goldklang, 1942 (Folder 5)
      - "Moje spostrzenia o Rosji Sowieckiej" by T. Kiersnowski, 1942 October (Folder 6)
      - "Polacy w Rosji po roku 1939" by Andzej Czaykowski, 1943 (Folder 7)
      - "Russian Captivity" by Jan Platak, 1943 (Folder 8)
      - "W ogrodzie diabla" by Andrzej Stocki, 1943 November (Folder 9-10)
      - "Cela Nr. 14" by Teodozja Elwicz, 1943 December (Folder 11)
      - "Liberation - Russian Style," by 1944 (Folder 12)
      - "Polacy w Zwiazku Sowieckim" by Stanislaw Kodz, 1944 February (Folder 13)
      - Untitled by Kazimierz Nawarski, 1944 March (Box 116., Folder 1)
      - "Compulsory Refugee," 1944 May (Folder 2)
      - "I Am Forced to Leave My Country," 1944 May (Folder 3)
    - Reports, memoranda, notes, and clippings relating to the Erlich and Alter Case, 1943 (Folder 4)
  - Children
    - Diaries
      - "Diary of a Polish Youth (Roman Szymanski) Deported to Russia," 1940 April-1942 March (Folder 5)
      - "Wyjatki z Pamietnika Dotyczace Lwowa 1939 I Okupacji Sowieckiej" by Roman Bader, 1939 September-1940 May (Folder 6)
    - Drawings (Folder 7)
    - Reports
      - General (Folder 8)
      - General (Box 117., Folder 1-3)
      - Bialostok Province (Folder 4)
      - Boys schools (Folder 5)
      - Gimnazijium Mech.-Lotnicze
        - Heliopolis (Box 118., Folder 1)
        - Sarafand (Folder 2)
      - Junacka Szkola Kadetow (Folder 3-4)
      - Lwow Province (Folder 5)
      - Lwow Province (Box 119., Folder 1)
      - Nowogrodek Province (Folder 2-3)
      - Polesie Province (Folder 4)
      - Stanislawow Province (Folder 5)
      - Szkola Mlodszych Ochotniczek (Box 120., Folder 1-6)
      - Szkola Mlodszych Ochotniczek (Box 121., Folder 1-2)
      - Tarnopol Province (Folder 3-4)
      - Wilno Province (Folder 5)
      - Wilno Province (Box 122., Folder 1)
      - Wolyn Province (Folder 2-5)
    - School essays, Teheran, 1942-1943 (Box 123., Folder 1-2)
  - Jews
    - List of Jewish social workers in the USSR, 1943 (Folder 3)
    - Memoir, "Moja 3 I polletnia wedrowka z Lezajska do Palestyny" by Rabbi Joel Landau, 1943 (Folder 4)
    - Reports, Polish Information Center, Jerusalem
      - 1943 (Folder 5-6)
      - 1944 (Folder 7)
      - 1944 (Box 124., Folder 1)
- POLES ABROAD, 1939-1943.
  Bulletins, correspondence, memoranda, reports, clippings, printed matter, and other material.
  - Poles
    - France (Box 124., Folder 2)
    - Great Britain
      - General (Folder 3-6)
      - Anglo-Polish Ballet (Box 125., Folder 1)
      - Association of Polish Engineers in Great Britain, 1941-1943 (Folder 2)
      - Polish emigre press on cultural relations between Poland and Great Britain, 1940-1943 (Folder 3)
      - Polish Red Cross, 1940-1942 (Folder 4)
      - Polish schools, 1941-1943 (Folder 5)
      - Polish scouts, 1943 (Folder 6)
      - Polish Students Association in Great Britain, 1941-1942 (Folder 7)
      - Polska Informacja Spoleczna, 1941-1942 (Folder 8)
    - United States
      - American Poles and Polish-American relations, 1941-1943 (Folder 9)
      - Polish-American press
        - 1942 (Box 126., Folder 1)
        - 1942-1943 (Folder 2)
  - Polish cultural activities
    - Art exhibits, 1941 (Folder 3)
    - Concerts, exhibits, lectures
      - 1940 (Folder 4)
      - 1941
        - January-February (Folder 5)
        - February-March (Folder 6)
        - April (Box 127., Folder 1)
        - May (Folder 2)
        - June (Folder 3)
        - July (Folder 4-5)
        - August-September (Box 128., Folder 1)
        - September (Folder 2)
        - October (Folder 3)
        - October-December (Folder 4)
      - 1942
        - January-April (Folder 5)
        - May-Decmber (Folder 6)
  - Polish emigre press, 1940-1943 (Box 129., Folder 1)
  - Women - Poland, 1942 (Folder 2-3)
  - World League of Poles Abroad (Swiatowy Zwiazek Polakow z Zagranicy)
    - General (Folder 4)
    - Bulletins, 1940-1942 (Folder 5)
    - Correspondence
      - 1940-1941 (Folder 6)
      - 1941 (Folder 7)
    - Leaflets, pamphlets, posters (Box 130., Folder 1)
    - Review of Polish emigre press, 1941-1942 (Folder 2)
- SUBJECT FILE, 1939-1945
  - Allied Forces
    - General
      - General (Box 130., Folder 3)
      - The Interallied Review, 1941-1942 (Folder 4)
    - Belgian News Agency, London. Bulletin, 1944
      - September (Folder 5)
      - October (Folder 6)
      - November (Folder 7)
      - December (Folder 8)
    - Belgium, 1941 (Folder 9)
  - Anglo-Jewish publications, 1942-1943 (Box 131., Folder 1-2)
  - Baltic Committee for Studies and Cooperation, New York (Folder 3)
  - Baltic States - History - Soviet occupation, 1939-1941 (Folder 4)
  - British Broadcasting Corporation. Polish Section. Correspondence and broadcasts
    - 1940
      - June-September (Folder 5)
      - October-November (Folder 6)
      - December (Folder 7)
    - 1941
      - January-February (Box 132., Folder 1)
      - March-April (Folder 2)
      - May-June (Folder 3)
      - July-August (Folder 4)
      - September (Folder 5)
      - October-December (Folder 6)
    - 1942 (Folder 7)
  - British Library of Information, New York. Bulletins from Britain
    - 1941 December-1942 April (Box 133., Folder 1)
    - 1942 May-June (Folder 2)
  - Copernicus Quadricentennial Anniversary, 1943 (Folder 3)
  - France - History - German occupation
    - 1940-1942 (Folder 4-5)
    - 1943 (Folder 6)
  - Germany - History-1939-1945 (Folder 7)
  - Gorka, Olgierd (Box 134., Folder 1-2)
  - Great Britain. Parliament
    - House of Commons. Parliamentary Debates. Official Reports. Issues dealing with Poland
      - 1941
        - May-June (Folder 3)
        - October-December (Folder 4)
      - 1942
        - January-February (Folder 5)
        - February-April (Folder 6)
        - May-June (Box 135., Folder 1)
    - House of Lords. Parliamentary Debates. Offical Reports. Issues dealing with Poland, 1942 January-August (Folder 2)
  - Hungarian News Survey, London, 1943 September-December (Folder 3)
  - Italy - Foreign relations - Germany, 1941-1943 (Folder 4)
  - Jews - Poland
    - Bulletin. Biuletyn Informacyjny dla spraw zydostwa Polskiego, 1941 June-August (Folder 5)
    - Notes by Dr. Edward Tohari on the fate of the Jews in the Warsaw Ghetto, Madrid, 1943 (Folder 6)
    - Subject file
      - Extermination of Jews in Poland
        - General (Folder 7)
        - Articles and sermons by Rabbi Jehosza Szpetman, 1944 (Folder 8)
      - Jews in the Polish Army, 1942-1944 (Folder 9)
      - Jews in the Polish Army, 1942-1944 (Box 136., Folder 1)
      - Polish-Jewish relations
        - 1940 (Folder 2)
        - 1941
          - January-April (Folder 3)
          - May-December (Folder 4)
        - 1943
          - January-June (Folder 5)
          - July-September (Folder 6)
          - October-December (Folder 7)
        - 1944
          - January-April (Box 137., Folder 1)
          - May-September (Folder 2)
  - Katyn Forest Massacre, 1940
    - Clippings (Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, memoranda, notes, relating to searches for missing Polish POWs
      - 1941-1942 (Folder 4)
      - 1943 (Folder 5)
    - Lists
      - German victims, 1943 April-September (Folder 6)
      - Identified victims, 1943 June (Folder 7)
      - Polish officers, POWs in Katyn, Starobielsk and Ostaszkow Camps, 1939-1940 (Box 138., Folder 1-2)
      - Polish POWs murdered in Katyn Forest (Folder 3-4)
      - Prisoners of war (Folder 5-6)
    - Press reports
      - German press, 1943 (Folder 7)
      - Portugese, Spanish, Swedish press, 1943 (Folder 8)
    - Printed matter (Box 139., Folder 1)
    - Radio broadcasts
      - Discovery of mass murder, 1943 April (Folder 2)
      - German radio, 1943 April-October (Folder 3)
      - Soviet radio, 1943-1944 (Folder 4)
    - Miscellany (Box 140.)
  - Lublin Committee (Polski Komitet Wyzwolenia Narodowego)
    - General (Box 141., Folder 1-3)
    - Correspondence
      - 1944 (Folder 4-5)
      - 1944-1945 (Folder 6)
  - Mikicinski, Samson (Folder 7)
  - Netherlands - History - German occupation, 1940-1945
    - Bulletins
      - Nederlandsche Regeerings Voorlichtingsdienst, 1944
        - October (Folder 8)
        - October-November (Box 142., Folder 1)
        - November (Folder 2-3)
        - November-December (Folder 4)
        - December (Folder 5-7)
      - Netherlands Press Agency
        - ANEP-ANETA Bulletin, 1944
          - September-October (Folder 8)
          - October-December (Box 143., Folder 1)
          - November-December (Folder 2)
        - Netherlands News Digest, 1944
          - September-November (Folder 3)
          - November-December (Folder 4)
    - Correspondence (Folder 5)
  - Poland. Ministerstwo Prac Kongresowych (Ministry of Preparatory Work Concerning the Peace Conference). Przeglad Literatury Politycznej, 1944: Nos. 36-40 (Folder 6)
  - Polish prisoners of war
    - General (Folder 7-8)
    - Soviet camps, 1939-1941 (Folder 9)
  - Polish publications
    - 1941
      - January-February (Box 144., Folder 1)
      - March-April (Folder 2)
      - May (Folder 3)
      - June (Folder 4)
      - October-November (Folder 5)
      - November (Folder 6)
      - December (Box 145., Folder 1)
    - 1942
      - January-September (Folder 2)
      - October-December (Folder 3)
    - 1943
      - January (Folder 4)
      - February (Folder 5)
      - March-May (Folder 6)
      - June-August (Folder 7)
      - September-October (Box 146., Folder 1)
      - November (Folder 2)
      - December (Folder 3)
    - 1944 (Folder 4)
  - Religion - Soviet Union (Folder 5)
  - Rotary Club of Hackney, London (Folder 6)
  - Soviet Union - History-1939-1945 (Folder 7)
  - Soviet Union - History-1939-1945 (Box 147., Folder 1)
  - Warsaw (Poland) - History - Uprising of 1944
    - Newspaper clippings (Folder 2)
    - Radio dispatches
      - General (Folder 3)
      - General Bor to Polish Government-in-Exile, 1944 August-September (Folder 4)
      - Underground authorities to Polish Government-in-Exile, 1944 August-September (Folder 5)
    - Report of the Polish Ministry of the Interior, London, 1944 December (Folder 6)
  - World War, 1939-1945
    - Campaigns - Eastern Front
      - 1941 (Folder 7)
      - 1941 (Box 148., Folder 1-2)
      - 1942
        - January-August (Folder 3)
        - September-December (Folder 4)
      - 1943 (Folder 5-6)
    - German press (Box 149., Folder 1)
    - Poland. Soviet press reports, 1944-1945 (Folder 2)
    - Underground movements
      - Austria, 1944 (Folder 3)
      - France
        - 1940-1941 (Folder 4)
        - 1941 (Folder 5)
      - Germany, 1942-1943 (Folder 6)
      - Yugoslavia, 1941 (Folder 7)
  - Miscellany (Folder 8-9)
- MICROFILMS, 1942-1943.
  - 11 microfilm reels of unidentified documents (Box 150.)
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1939-1945
  - 297 prints depicting Polish military personnel and military operations during World War II (Folder A-D)
  - 14 prints depicting scenes in Warsaw during World War II (Folder E)
  - 51 prints depicting German atrocities, destruction and concentration camps in Poland during World War II (Folder F)
  - 39 prints depicting foreign and Polish statesmen, military officers, and dignitaries (Folder G)
  - 99 prints depicting Polish citizens, daily scenes and various places of interest in Poland during World War II (Folder H)
  - 64 prints depicting scenes at the site of the Katyn Forest Massacre and documents of the investigation (Box 151., Folder 1)
  - 45 prints depicting scenes at the site of the Katyn Forest Massacre and documents of the investigation (Folder 2)
- RELEASE CERTIFICATES ("UDOSTOVERENIA"), 1941 August-September
  - Aba - Ben (Box 152., Folder 1-14)
  - Ber - Bra (Box 153., Folder 1-18)
  - Bre - Cw (Box 154., Folder 1-16)
  - Cyb - Dol (Box 155., Folder 1-17)
  - Dom - Fej (Box 156., Folder 1-14)
  - Fel - Ga (Box 157., Folder 1-13)
  - Gdy - Gri (Box 158., Folder 1-14)
  - Gro - Hle (Box 159., Folder 1-13)
  - Hoc - Jarm (Box 160., Folder 1-12)
  - Jarn - Kam (Box 161., Folder 1-14)
  - Kan - Kno (Box 162., Folder 1-14)
  - Koa - Kos (Box 163., Folder 1-15)
  - Kot - Krz (Box 164., Folder 1-15)
  - Ksi - Laz (Box 165., Folder 1-17)
  - Leb - L/a (Box 166., Folder 1-15)
  - Lob - Man (Box 167., Folder 1-16)
  - Mar - Mil (Box 168., Folder 1-16)
  - Min - Myz (Box 169., Folder 1-15)
  - Nab - Oku (Box 170., Folder 1-14)
  - Ola - Pa (Box 171., Folder 1-16)
  - Pcz - Pod (Box 172., Folder 1-18)
  - Pog - Raj (Box 173., Folder 1-16)
  - Rak - Roz (Box 174., Folder 1-13)
  - Rub - Scy (Box 175., Folder 1-16)
  - Seb - Soz (Box 176., Folder 1-17)
  - Spi - Syt (Box 177., Folder 1-14)
  - Sza - Szo (Box 178., Folder 1-14)
  - Szp - Sw (Box 179., Folder 1-13)
  - Tab - Uzi (Box 180., Folder 1-14)
  - Wac - Wir (Box 181., Folder 1-12)
  - Wis - Wuz (Box 182., Folder 1-14)
  - Zab - Zre (Box 183., Folder 1-14)
  - Zu - Zw (Box 184., Folder 1-8)
- REPORTS OF POLISH DEPORTEES, 1941
  - Lwow Province
    - Originals
      - Lwow City (Box 185., Folder 1-19)
      - Lwow County (Folder 20)
      - Bobrka County (Box 186., Folder 1)
      - Brzozow County (Folder 2)
      - Dobromil County (Folder 3)
      - Drohobycz County (Folder 4)
      - Grodek Jagiellonski County (Folder 5)
      - Jaroslaw County (Folder 6)
      - Jaworow County (Folder 7)
      - Lesko County (Folder 8)
      - Lubaczow County (Folder 9)
      - Mosciska County (Folder 10)
      - Przemysl County (Box 187., Folder 1)
      - Przeworsk County (Folder 2)
      - Rawa Ruska County (Folder 3)
      - Rudki County (Folder 4)
      - Rzeszow County (Folder 5)
      - Sambor County (Folder 6)
      - Sanok County (Folder 7)
      - Turka County (Folder 8)
      - Zolkiew County (Folder 9)
      - Zydaczow County (Folder 10)
    - Copies and excerpts (Box 188-193.)
    - Related studies (Box 194-195.)
  - Tarnopol Province
    - Originals
      - Tarnopol City (Box 196., Folder 1-3)
      - Tarnopol County (Folder 4)
      - Borszczow County (Folder 5-6)
      - Brody County (Folder 7-8)
      - Brzezany County (Folder 9)
      - Buczacz County (Folder 10)
      - Czortkow County (Folder 11)
      - Kamionka Strumilowa County (Folder 12)
      - Kopyczynce County (Box 197., Folder 1-2)
      - Podhajce County (Folder 3)
      - Przemyslany County (Folder 4)
      - Radziechow County (Folder 5)
      - Skalat County (Folder 6)
      - Trembowla County (Folder 7-8)
      - Zaleszczyki County (Folder 9)
      - Zbaraz County (Folder 10)
      - Zborow County (Folder 11)
      - Zloczow County (Folder 12)
    - Copies and excerpts (Box 198-201.)
    - Related studies (Box 202.)
  - Stanislawow Province
    - Originals
      - Dolina County (Box 203., Folder 1)
      - Horodenka County (Folder 2)
      - Kalusz County (Folder 3)
      - Kolomyja County (Folder 4)
      - Kosow Huculski County (Folder 5)
      - Nadworna County (Folder 6)
      - Rohatyn County (Folder 7)
      - Sniatyn County (Folder 8)
      - Stanislawow County (Folder 9-12)
      - Stryj County (Folder 13)
      - Tlumacz County (Folder 14)
      - Zydaczow County (Folder 15)
    - Copies and excerpts (Box 204-206.)
    - Related studies (Box 207-208.)
  - Wolyn Province
    - Originals
      - Dubno County (Box 209., Folder 1-2)
      - Horochow County (Folder 3-4)
      - Horodenka County (Folder 5)
      - Kostopol County (Folder 6)
      - Kowel County (Folder 7-8)
      - Krzemieniec County (Folder 9-12)
      - Luboml County (Folder 13)
      - Luck City (Box 210., Folder 1)
      - Luck County (Folder 2-4)
      - Rowne City (Folder 5)
      - Rowne County (Folder 6-7)
      - Sarny City (Folder 8)
      - Sarny County (Folder 9-10)
      - Wlodzimierz City (Folder 11)
      - Wlodzimierz County (Folder 12)
      - Zdolbunow City (Folder 13)
      - Zdolbunow County (Folder 14)
      - Unidentified counties (Folder 15)
    - Copies and excerpts (Box 211-214.)
    - Related studies (Box 215-216.)
  - Polesie Province
    - Originals
      - Brzesc n/Bugiem City (Box 217., Folder 1-2)
      - Brzesc n/Bugiem County (Folder 3)
      - Drohiczyn County (Folder 4)
      - Kamien Koszyrski County (Folder 5)
      - Kobryn County (Folder 6)
      - Kosow Poleski City (Folder 7)
      - Kosow Poleski County (Folder 8)
      - Luniniec City (Folder 9)
      - Luniniec County (Folder 10-11)
      - Pinsk City (Folder 12)
      - Pinsk County (Folder 13-14)
      - Pruzana City (Folder 15)
      - Pruzana County (Folder 16)
      - Stolin City (Folder 17)
      - Stolin County (Folder 18)
    - Copies and excerpts (Box 218-220.)
    - Related studies (Box 221.)
  - Bialystok Province
    - Originals
      - Augustow City (Box 222., Folder 1)
      - Augustow County (Folder 2)
      - Bialystok City (Folder 3-6)
      - Bialystok County (Folder 7-9)
      - Bielsk Podlaski City (Folder 10)
      - Bielsk Podlaski County (Folder 11-14)
      - Grodno City (Box 223., Folder 1-2)
      - Grodno County (Folder 3-4)
      - Sokolka County (Folder 5)
      - Szczuczyn County (Folder 6)
      - Wolkowysk City (Folder 7)
      - Wolkowysk County (Folder 8-10)
      - Wysokie Mazowieckie City (Folder 11)
      - Wysokie Mazowieckie County (Folder 12)
    - Copies and excerpts (Box 224-228.)
    - Related studies (Box 229.)
  - Nowogrodek Province
    - Originals
      - Baranowicze City (Box 230., Folder 1)
      - Baranowicze County (Folder 2-4)
      - Lida City (Folder 5)
      - Lida County (Folder 6-7)
      - Nieswiez City (Folder 8)
      - Nieswiez County (Folder 9-11)
      - Nowogrodek City (Folder 12)
      - Nowogrodek County (Folder 13-14)
      - Slonim City (Box 231., Folder 1)
      - Slonim County (Folder 2)
      - Stolpce City (Folder 3)
      - Stolpce County (Folder 4)
      - Szczuczyn City (Folder 5)
      - Szczuczyn County (Folder 6-7)
      - Wolozyn City (Folder 8)
      - Wolozyn County (Folder 9-10)
    - Copies and excerpts (Box 232-234.)
    - Related studies (Box 235.)
  - Wilno Province
    - Originals
      - Wilno City (Box 236., Folder 1-4)
      - Wilno County (Folder 5)
      - Braslaw County (Folder 6-7)
      - Dzisna City (Folder 8)
      - Dzisna County (Folder 9-11)
      - Molodeczno City (Folder 12)
      - Molodeczno County (Folder 13-14)
      - Oszmiana City (Box 237., Folder 1)
      - Oszmiana County (Folder 2)
      - Postawy City (Folder 3)
      - Postawy County (Folder 4-5)
      - Swieciany City (Folder 6)
      - Swieciany County (Folder 7-8)
      - Wilejka City (Folder 9)
      - Wilejka County (Folder 10-12)
      - Wilno-Troki County (Folder 13-15)
    - Copies and excerpts (Box 238-242.)
    - Related studies (Box 243-244.)
  - Lublin Province (Box 245., Folder 1)
  - Warszawa Province
    - Originals
      - Lomza City (Folder 2)
      - Lomza County (Folder 3-5)
      - Ostrow Mazowiecka County (Folder 6)
      - Unidentified counties (Folder 7)
    - Copies and excerpts (Folder 8-9)
    - Related studies (Folder 10-13)
  - Multiple provinces (bound notebooks containing several reports from different localities of Soviet-occupied Poland) (Box 246., Folder 1-2)
  - Unidentified provinces (Folder 3-4)
  - Unidentified names (Folder 5)
  - Miscellany
    - Lists of deportees by number
      - #610-1990 (Box 247., Folder 1)
      - #1991-4000 (Folder 2)
      - #4001-4600 (Folder 3)
      - #4630-8176 (Folder 4)
      - #8201-11323 (Folder 5)
    - Reports by Polish prisoners of war
      - German-occupied Poland (Folder 6)
      - Soviet-occupied Poland (Folder 7-8)
    - Various material relating to Soviet-occupied Poland (census data, commune registers, historical outlines)
      - Provinces of Lwow, Tarnopol, Stanislawow, Wolyn (Folder 9)
      - Provinces of Polesie, Bialystok, Nowogrodek, Wilno (Folder 10)
    - Miscellany. Includes instructions on how to fill out questionnaires (Folder 11)